[{"question":" By convention, what name is used for the first key in a JSON schema?","options":[{"text":"schema","correct":false},{"text":"\\$schema","correct":true},{"text":"JsonSchema","correct":false},{"text":"JSONschema","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Which code is the closest JSON equivalent of the data shown?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```json\n{\n  \"red\": \"red\",\n  \"blue\": \"blue\"\n}\n```"},{"question":" Which JavaScript method converts a JavaScript value to Json?","options":[{"text":"JSON.parse()","correct":false},{"text":"JSON.stringify()","correct":true},{"text":"JSON.toString()","correct":false},{"text":"JSON.objectify()","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Which data type is NOT part of JSON standard?","options":[{"text":"string","correct":false},{"text":"number","correct":false},{"text":"date","correct":true},{"text":"array","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Which term is commonly used to refer to converting data to JSON?","options":[{"text":"unpacking","correct":false},{"text":"serialization","correct":true},{"text":"deserialization","correct":false},{"text":"parsing","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Which code uses the correct JSON syntax to encode the key/value pair shown?","options":[{"text":"\"accountNum\": \"00060504\"","correct":true},{"text":"accountNum: \"00060504\"","correct":false},{"text":"\"accountNum\": 00060504","correct":false},{"text":"accountNum: 00060504","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" What character do you specify before a JSON control character when you want to use that control characters as a literal part of a string?","options":[{"text":"`/`","correct":false},{"text":"`\\`","correct":true},{"text":"`:`","correct":false},{"text":"`{`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Which date type is part of the JSON standard?","options":[{"text":"Boolean","correct":true},{"text":"map","correct":false},{"text":"promise","correct":false},{"text":"function","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Which key name is used to specify properties that must be included for JSON to be valid?","options":[{"text":"important","correct":false},{"text":"base","correct":false},{"text":"core","correct":false},{"text":"required","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which is the valid JSON equivalent of the data shown?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```json\n{\n  \"photo\": {\n    \"width\": \"1600\",\n    \"height\": \"900\",\n    \"binaries\": {\n      \"url\": \"https://www.example.com/images/34097349843\",\n      \"thumbnail\": \"https://www.example.com/images/thumbs/34097349843\"\n    },\n    \"animated\": \"false\",\n    \"tags\": [\"116\", \"943\", \"234\", \"38793\"]\n  }\n}\n```"},{"question":". How do you store several paragraphs of text as a string in JSON?","options":[{"text":"Escape all whitespaces expect space characters.","correct":true},{"text":"Escape line breaks.","correct":false},{"text":"Escape paragraphs.","correct":false},{"text":"Remove all whitespaces","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What data type is represented by the value of the key/value pair shown?","options":[{"text":"string","correct":false},{"text":"Boolean","correct":true},{"text":"number","correct":false},{"text":"object","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". If you need to store the loggedIn status of a user in JSON as a boolean, what is the correct syntax?","options":[{"text":"\"loggedIn\": (true)","correct":false},{"text":"loggedIn: \"true\"","correct":false},{"text":"\"loggedIn\": true","correct":true},{"text":"loggedIn: {true}","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What does JSON with padding (JSON-P) use to make a request?","options":[{"text":"an `<origin>` element","correct":false},{"text":"a header request","correct":false},{"text":"the `<script>` element","correct":true},{"text":"the XMLHttpRequest object","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which value is supported in the JSON specifications?","options":[{"text":"undefined","correct":false},{"text":"infinity","correct":false},{"text":"NaN","correct":false},{"text":"null","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which JavaScript method converts a Json to JavaScript value?","options":[{"text":"JSON.parse()","correct":true},{"text":"JSON.stringify()","correct":false},{"text":"JSON.toString()","correct":false},{"text":"JSON.objectify()","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Transferring JSON information from client to server and back again often includes HTTP requests. Match each method with the best choice describing its use.","options":[{"text":"1.POST 2.DELETE 3.OPTIONS 4.HEADER 5.GET 6.PUT","correct":false},{"text":"1.POST 2.PUT 3.HEADER 4.OPTIONS 5.GET 6.DELETE","correct":false},{"text":"1.POST 2.DELETE 3.OPTIONS 4.HEADER 5.GET 6.PUT","correct":false},{"text":"1.POST 2.PUT 3.HEADER 4.OPTIONS 5.GET 6.DELETE","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which code uses valid JSON syntax for the text \"Centennial Olympics?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true}],"illustrator":"```json\n{\n  \"host\": \"Atlanta\",\n  \"year\": 1996,\n  \"comments\": \"Centennial Olympics\"\n}\n```"},{"question":". Can trailing commas be used in objects and arrays?","options":[{"text":"yes","correct":false},{"text":"only if there is more than one item","correct":false},{"text":"no","correct":true},{"text":"only when arrays and objects contain more than 10 items","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which whitespace characters should be escaped within a string?","options":[{"text":"All whitespace is allowed.","correct":false},{"text":"double quotes, slashes new lines, and carriage returns","correct":false},{"text":"new lines and carriage returns only","correct":true},{"text":"double quotes only","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which is supported by YAML but not supported by JSON?","options":[{"text":"nested","correct":false},{"text":"comments","correct":true},{"text":"arrays","correct":false},{"text":"null values","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which is an invalid JSON value?","options":[{"text":"\"'|=(_)(X 72(_)|\\/||\\*'\"","correct":false},{"text":"\"|=(_)(X 72(_)|\\/||\\*\"","correct":false},{"text":"\"|=(_)(X\\\" \\\"72(_)|\\/||\\*\"","correct":false},{"text":"\"\\s(_)(X 72(_)|\\/||\\*\"","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How do you encode a date in JSON?","options":[{"text":"Convert the date to UTC and enclose in quotes.","correct":false},{"text":"Encode the date as string using the ISO-8601 date format.","correct":true},{"text":"Wrap the date in double quotes.","correct":false},{"text":"Add a \"date\" key to your object and include the date as string.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Whatâ€™s wrong with this JavaScript?","options":[{"text":"JSON should be wrapped with curly braces.","correct":false},{"text":"JSON.parse() is missing an argument.","correct":false},{"text":"The value supplied to JSON.parse() is not a string.","correct":true},{"text":"Nothing is wrong with it.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What does this JavaScript code print?","options":[{"text":"A","correct":true},{"text":"B","correct":false},{"text":"C","correct":false},{"text":"D","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nnull\nnull\nnull\n```"},{"question":". What tool might you use to validate your JSON?","options":[{"text":"JSONLint","correct":true},{"text":"ValidateJSON","correct":false},{"text":"JSONFiddle","correct":false},{"text":"TextEdit","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What characters denote strings in JSON?","options":[{"text":"double quotes","correct":true},{"text":"smart (curly) quotes","correct":false},{"text":"single or double quotes","correct":false},{"text":"single quotes","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which code is a valid JSON equivalent of the key/value pair shown that also preserves the data type? `constant: 6.022E23`","options":[{"text":"`\"constant\": \"6.022E23\"`","correct":true},{"text":"`\"constant\": \"6\\.022\\E23\"`","correct":false},{"text":"`constant: 6.022E23`","correct":false},{"text":"`constant: \"6.022E23\"`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which element is added to the DOM to create a JSON-P request?","options":[{"text":"`<object>`","correct":false},{"text":"`<script>`","correct":true},{"text":"`<json>`","correct":false},{"text":"`<meta>`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Why do so many APIs use JSON?","options":[{"text":"Because it's object-based.","correct":false},{"text":"Because it's a simple and adaptable format for sharing data.","correct":false},{"text":"Because it's based on JavaScript.","correct":true},{"text":"Because it is derived from SGML.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to assemble a list of members, but your JSON is not parsing correctly. How do you change it?","options":[{"text":"A","correct":true},{"text":"B","correct":false},{"text":"C","correct":false},{"text":"D","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```json\n{\n  \"avengers\": {[\n    \"iron man\",\n    \"hulk\",\n    \"thor\",\n    \"black widow\",\n    \"ant man\",\n    \"spider man\"\n  ]}\n}\n```"},{"question":". When building dynamic web applications using AJAX, developers originally used the \\_\\_\\_\\_ data format, which has since been replaced by JSON.","options":[{"text":"XML","correct":true},{"text":"GRAPHQL","correct":false},{"text":"REST","correct":false},{"text":"SOAP","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How is a true boolean value represented in JSON?","options":[{"text":"TRUE","correct":false},{"text":"\"true\"","correct":false},{"text":"1","correct":false},{"text":"true","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which array is valid JSON?","options":[{"text":"['tatooine', 'hoth', 'dagobah']","correct":false},{"text":"[tatooine, hoth, dagobah]","correct":false},{"text":"[\"tatooine\", \"hoth\", \"dagobah\",]","correct":false},{"text":"[\"tatooine\", \"hoth\", \"dagobah\"]","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What data type is encoded in the outermost component of the JSON shown?","options":[{"text":"object","correct":false},{"text":"array","correct":true},{"text":"number","correct":false},{"text":"string","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```json\n[\n  {\n    \"year\": 2024\n  },\n  {\n    \"location\": \"unknown\"\n  }\n]\n```"},{"question":". Which is ignored by JSON but treated as significant by YAML?","options":[{"text":"trailing commas","correct":false},{"text":"trailing decimals","correct":false},{"text":"whitespace","correct":false},{"text":"leading zeroes","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". When you need to set the value of a key in JSON to be blank, what is the correct syntax for the empty value?","options":[{"text":"FALSE","correct":false},{"text":"0","correct":false},{"text":"\"\"","correct":false},{"text":"null","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How do you assign a number value in JSON?","options":[{"text":"Escape the number with a backslash.","correct":false},{"text":"Enclose the number in double quotes.","correct":false},{"text":"Enclose the number in single quotes.","correct":false},{"text":"Leave the number as is.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which code uses the correct JSON syntax for encoding a key/value pair with a null value?","options":[{"text":"\"lastVisit\": \"null\"","correct":true},{"text":"lastVisit: null","correct":false},{"text":"\"lastVisit\": 0","correct":false},{"text":"\"lastVisit\": undefined","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which reference to the Unicode character U+1F602 complies with the JSON standard?","options":[{"text":"128514","correct":false},{"text":"d83dde02","correct":false},{"text":"\\uD83D\\uDE02","correct":true},{"text":"\\&#128514;","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which code uses the correct JSON syntax for a key/Value pair containing a string?","options":[{"text":"\"largest\": \"blue whale\"","correct":true},{"text":"largest: 'blue whale'","correct":false},{"text":"'largest': 'blue whale'","correct":false},{"text":"largest: \"blue whale\"","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which key name is used to specify data type in a JSON schema?","options":[{"text":"data","correct":false},{"text":"schemadata","correct":false},{"text":"schematype","correct":false},{"text":"type","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which code is a valid JSON equivalent of the key/value pair shown that also preserves the original value?","options":[{"text":"\"UPC\": \\043875","correct":false},{"text":"UPC: \"043875\"","correct":false},{"text":"\"UPC\": 043875","correct":false},{"text":"UPC: '043875'","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which data format is a JSON schema written in?","options":[{"text":"markdown","correct":false},{"text":"YAML","correct":false},{"text":"XML","correct":false},{"text":"JSON","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which code is valid JSON equivalent of the key/value pair shown that also preserves the data type?","options":[{"text":"\"variance\": \"-0.0823\"","correct":true},{"text":"variance: \"-0.0823\"","correct":false},{"text":"\"variance\": \"\\-0.0823\"","correct":false},{"text":"variance: -0.0823","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". With what character should key/value pairs be separated?","options":[{"text":"colon","correct":true},{"text":"space","correct":false},{"text":"semicolon","correct":false},{"text":"comma","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What character separates keys from values?","options":[{"text":":","correct":true},{"text":"->","correct":false},{"text":"::","correct":false},{"text":".","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". If a string contains line breaks, what should you do?","options":[{"text":"Wrap line breaks in single quotation marks","correct":false},{"text":"Make no changes, because whitespace is allowed","correct":false},{"text":"Replace any line breaks with `\\r`","correct":false},{"text":"Replace any line breaks with `\\n`","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which number types are available in javascript but not supported in json?","options":[{"text":"Fractional and Transcendental","correct":false},{"text":"Infinity or Rational","correct":false},{"text":"Rational and Irrational","correct":false},{"text":"Infinity or NaN","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How should a date value be stored in JSON?","options":[{"text":"As a string with quotes","correct":false},{"text":"As a string without quotes","correct":false},{"text":"As a string in ISO 8583 format","correct":false},{"text":"As a string in ISO 8601 format","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Is the JSON code shown here valid?","options":[{"text":"No, emojis must be escaped with a backslash.","correct":false},{"text":"No, JSON strings are not allowed to use emojis.","correct":false},{"text":"No, emojis should never be enclosed with double quotes.","correct":false},{"text":"Yes, emojis are valid characters because JSON strings are unicode.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What data structure do you use to encode ordered information?","options":[{"text":"list","correct":false},{"text":"array","correct":true},{"text":"struct","correct":false},{"text":"indexed hash","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What are valid values in JSON?","options":[{"text":"arrays, strings, numbers, true/false","correct":false},{"text":"hashes, arrays, strings, numbers, booleans, null","correct":false},{"text":"arrays, objects, lists, strings, numbers, booleans","correct":false},{"text":"objects, arrays, strings, numbers, booleans, null","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which key format is valid JSON?","options":[{"text":"key: \"value\"","correct":false},{"text":"\"key\": \"value\"","correct":true},{"text":"key, \"value\"","correct":false},{"text":"'key': 'value'","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What data type is encoded in the outermost component of the JSON shown?","options":[{"text":"number","correct":false},{"text":"array","correct":false},{"text":"string","correct":false},{"text":"object","correct":true}],"illustrator":"```json\n{\n  \"result\": [\n    {\n      \"year\": 2024\n    },\n    {\n      \"location\": \"unknown\"\n    }\n  ]\n}\n```"},{"question":". What's wrong with this JSON object?","options":[{"text":"Key/value pairs should be separated by semicolons.","correct":false},{"text":"Keys should be enclosed with double quotes.","correct":true},{"text":"Key/value pairs should always have a trailing comma.","correct":false},{"text":"Keys and values should be enclosed with single quotes.","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```json\n{\n  \"series\": \"Star Trek\",\n  \"episodes\": \"The Trouble with Tribbles\"\n}\n```"},{"question":". How should comments be formatted in JSON?","options":[{"text":"Wrap the comments in single quotes and place it at the bottom of the file.","correct":false},{"text":"Wrap the comments in double parentheses.","correct":false},{"text":"Escape comments by placing two slashes at the start of the comment.","correct":false},{"text":"JSON does not support comments.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How would you make the following string valid in JSON?","options":[{"text":"name: \"bb-8\"","correct":false},{"text":"\"name\": \\'bb-8\\'","correct":false},{"text":"\"name\": \"bb-8\"","correct":true},{"text":"\"name\": bb-8","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```json\n\"name\": 'bb-8'\n```"},{"question":". How are values separated in JSON?","options":[{"text":"with brackets","correct":false},{"text":"with colons","correct":false},{"text":"with commas","correct":true},{"text":"with parentheses","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". With which programming language is JSON best used?","options":[{"text":"any language, as JSON is language agnostic.","correct":true},{"text":"Ruby","correct":false},{"text":"JavaScript","correct":false},{"text":"Python","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What values can arrays contain?","options":[{"text":"only numbers","correct":false},{"text":"any valid JSON value","correct":true},{"text":"only strings and numbers","correct":false},{"text":"only strings","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What technique can be used to represent complex objects with JSON?","options":[{"text":"reserialization","correct":false},{"text":"nesting","correct":true},{"text":"memorization","correct":false},{"text":"minimization","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What characters are used to enclose an array?","options":[{"text":"[]","correct":true},{"text":"{}","correct":false},{"text":"\"\"","correct":false},{"text":"()","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the official MIME type for JSON?","options":[{"text":"text/json","correct":false},{"text":"text/javascript","correct":false},{"text":"application/json","correct":true},{"text":"data/json","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What character cannot be part of string within JSON without additional formatting?","options":[{"text":"/","correct":false},{"text":"\"","correct":true},{"text":"-","correct":false},{"text":":","correct":false}],"illustrator":""}]